# Arman Hossain

#### Software Engineer

With 20+ years of programming and a decade in the professional tech arena, I excel in web, mobile, and data scraping. I'm not just a software engineer - I'm your go-to digital problem solver, turning raw data into actionable insights.



$\sim$	armans.postbox@gmail	com
I / T \		

Dhaka, Bangladesh

in linkedin.com/in/armanhossain

github.com/arman-bd

+8801773508050

🔞 arman-bd.github.io

S arman bd

medium.com/@arman-bd

### **SKILLS**

Web Scraping

Reverse Engineering

Python

Back-End

Front-End

CI/CD

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Integration Engineer

#### Terminal49

01/2023 - Present

(Remote) SF, California, USA

Terminal49 is a shipping container tracking and execution platform. Global container tracking via a single API and dashboard.

Achievements/Tasks

- Web scraping and parsing using Scrapy and Rails
- Data Integration on the Rails Project
- Maintaining the CI/CD Pipeline

Contact: Matt Turner - matt@terminal49.com

# Chief Technology Officer

HelloTask Platform Ltd.

05/2022 - 12/2022 Dhaka, Bangladesh

HelloTask is an app-based reliable domestic worker sourcing platform in Bangladesh. We connect verified workers to users in real-time.

Achievements/Tasks

- Software Development Team Management
- Project Management: JIRA
- Software Development: Flask, Nest, and Next
- Cloud Management: AWS, Azure

Contact: Mehedi Shoron - shoron@hellotask.app

### Deputy General Manager, IT

Shakti Foundation

Dhaka, Bangladesh

01/2021 - 05/2022 Shakti Foundation is a non-government organization committed to the economic and social empowerment of disadvantaged women across Bangladesh.

- Achievements/Tasks
- Offline First Fin-Tech Mobile App Development for Microfinance and SME.
- Piloting, Training and Field Level Deployment.
- Project Life Cycle Maintenance (SDLC).

Contact: Md Abdur Rashid Mamun - smamun@shakti.com.bd

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineer / Team Lead

#### Riseup Labs

09/2019 - 12/2020 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Riseup Labs is an ISO 9001 and 27001-certified next-generation global IT service and technology solution provider company in Bangladesh.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Team Lead & Project Lifecycle Management.
- Software Architecture Design.
- App Development, Front-End & Back-End Development.
- Project Development and Maintenance for the United Nations, UNICEF, and the Government of Bangladesh.

Contact: Emanul Haque Ratul - ratul@riseuplabs.com

#### Software Developer

#### AppCon Soft

11/2014 - 04/2017 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Achievements/Tasks

- Software Development, Web-Development
- Search Engine Architecture and Design
- Web-Crawler, Web-Scraper Design
- Selenium Based Automation

Contact: Abdullah Al Sayeed - sayeedcodex@gmail.com

#### **Programmer**

#### AppsDrone (Project)

02/2013 - 10/2014

AppsDrone is an android application discovery service which helps it's user to find best apps and games through different android market places.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Web Development, Data Analysis.
- Android Marketplace Data Analysis.
- Marketplace Report Generation.
- Web Scraping, Parsing and Data Mapping.
- Apache Solr based Search Solution.

### **EDUCATION**

## **B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering**

Shanto-Mariam University of Creative Technology

01/2016 - 06/2020 Dhaka, Bangladesh

### **LANGUAGES**

English Bangla

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency

### **SOFT SKILLS**

Public Speaking Presentatio

Team Management

## **REFERENCES**

Abdullah Al Sayeed, CTO, IndexIA Ltd

Contact: sayeedcodex@gmail.com - +8801979442211